Never Follow
Take the Lead is a drama, music film directed by Liz Friedlander.
A former professional dancer volunteers to teach dance in the New York public school system and, while his
background first clashes with his students' tastes, together they create a completely new style of dance.
Based on the story of ballroom dancer, Pierre Dulane.
Pierre Dulaine, played by Antonio Banderas.
Rock, played by Rob Brown.
LaRhette, played by Yaya DaCosta.
Augustine James, played by Alfre Woodard.
Mr. Temple, played by John Ortiz.
Tina, played by Laura Benanti.
Take the Lead is a 2006 American drama dance film directed by Liz Friedlander in her feature directional debut and
starring Antonio Banderas as dance instructor Pierre Dulaine, the founder of Dancing Classrooms.
It also stars Alfre Woodard, John Ortiz, Rob Brown, Yaya
DaCosta, Dante Basco, Elijah Kelley, and Jenna Dewan.
The film was released on April 7, 2006.
Although based in New York City, it was filmed in Toronto.
Stock footage of various locations in New York City was used.
The film explores themes of dance, dancing master, woman director.
The tone is emotional.